<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>blogging on Hack The Planet</title>
    <link>https://brandontreb.ngrok.io/tags/blogging/</link>
    <description></description>
    
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 15:15:55 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Another) Blogging Isn’t Dead Post</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.ngrok.io/2023/01/26/u722z0gbkf24kybk7dykn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 15:15:55 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (|ZeroCool|)</author><guid>https://brandontreb.ngrok.io/2023/01/26/u722z0gbkf24kybk7dykn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://brandontreb.ngrok.io/uploads/2023/download?ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MXxhbGx8fHx8fHx8fHwxNjc0NzM5NjEw&amp;amp;force=true&amp;amp;w=640&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dariusforoux.com/blogging-not-dying/&#34;&gt;No, Blogging Is Not Dying Anytime Soon  - Darius Foroux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still, people who read have always been in the minority. And I think that’s what most people who think that “video is the future” don’t get. Sure, people are getting lazier and they want you to feed them content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But think about it. Do you really want to serve those types of people?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt; “Blogging Is Not Dead” posts because I love to blog and often wonder if it’s a waste of time. It’s always reassuring to hear new perspectives on this topic and reaffirm the WHYs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a wildly successful blog in the early 2000’s which I sold for almost nothing (I was a broke college kid and didn’t understand business) and have yet to recreate that sort of blogging success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s helpful to recognize that these days that I probably won’t be a prominent blogger again but that doesn’t mean blogging can’t be an important part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I blog now for these reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning New concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mental Clarity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve communication skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build Community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;???&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and I’m more than ok with that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back To My Roots</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.ngrok.io/2013/06/12/back-to-my-roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (|ZeroCool|)</author><guid>https://brandontreb.ngrok.io/2013/06/12/back-to-my-roots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote my very first blog post back in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icodeblog.com/2008/07/22/icodeblog-launched/&#34;&gt;July of 2008&lt;/a&gt; when I start &lt;a href=&#34;http://iCodeBlog.com&#34;&gt;iCodeBlog.com&lt;/a&gt;.  I started the blog because I saw a huge need for iOS development tutorials on the web and really wanted to help others as I progressed in my development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, quite a bit has changed since then.  I have written books, spoken at conferences, and built and shipped over 40 iOS applications.  Since selling iCodeblog in 2009, I have really let my passion for blogging fizzle.  For the first 2 years of the iCode sale, I wasn’t allowed to write tutorials on any other site.  This was very discouraging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have guest blogged iOS tutorials on several sites including &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile.tutsplus.com/author/brandon-trebitowski/&#34;&gt;mobile.tutsplus.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raywenderlich.com/author/brandontreb&#34;&gt;raywenderlich.com&lt;/a&gt;.  This has been pretty hit or miss for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of recent, I have become an &lt;a href=&#34;http://brandontreb.com/what-i-learned-in-my-first-month-being-a-contract-ios-developer&#34;&gt;independent iOS developer&lt;/a&gt; and have been solving quite a few hard problems and coming up with some interesting solutions on projects that I have been a part of.  I now want to share some of those solutions with the iOS community in the form of tutorial blog posts.  These come in all shapes in sizes from cool UIKit hacks to building simple backend services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I say that I want to “get back to my roots”, I really want to start consistently blogging again and educating other developers using the knowledge I have gained over the years.  So stick around, &lt;a href=&#34;http://brandontreb.com/feed&#34;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/brandontreb&#34;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;, and please don’t hesitate to suggest tutorial ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy hacking…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/share&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>