<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fitness on Brandontreb</title>
    <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/fitness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fitness on Brandontreb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>brandontreb@gmail.com</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>brandontreb@gmail.com</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 17:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/fitness/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2023/02/04/krrtbya3e6e2oqn9b639p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2023/02/04/krrtbya3e6e2oqn9b639p3/</guid>
      <description>Since seeing a bobcat in The Bosque a few months ago, I now am constantly looking over my shoulder while I’m out there on my runs.
It’s both exciting and terrifying. 🏃‍♂️</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2023/01/09/tw3u6tbbewpfbqosls6shi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 20:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2023/01/09/tw3u6tbbewpfbqosls6shi/</guid>
      <description>I switched from weight lifting to calisthenics in the gym over a year ago. It was one of the best decisions ever.
A year in, and I still get excited to go every single time.
It feels like I’m a kid again getting to play on the playground at recess. 🤸</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Albuquerque Marathon Training</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/02/21/albuquerque-marathon-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/02/21/albuquerque-marathon-training/</guid>
      <description>Well, I have finally decided to put my money where my mouth is when it comes to fitness and train up for a half marathon! The marathon I’m training for is the Albuquerque Half Marathon on Saturday, April 16th at 8 am (that logo is such an eyesore).
Two months seems like a relatively short time to prepare, especially for my first “real” run, however I am just aiming to finish rather than being competitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Your Life In 2011</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/23/changing-your-life-in-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/23/changing-your-life-in-2011/</guid>
      <description>For this blog post, I decided to take a small break from my Twitter Client for Mac tutorial series and discuss something a little more useful 😉 . I felt that a fitness post would be most appropriate around this time of year as all of our “Geek Guts” begin expanding.
My Fitness Story It’s December 23rd and as we gear up for Christmas, we are also compiling our New Year’s resolutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology &#43; Fitness = &lt;3 :: 3 Apps That Will Keep Even The Laziest Geek In Shape</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/01/technology-fitness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/01/technology-fitness/</guid>
      <description>If you are reading this post you are most likely a geek. It’s true, otherwise if you were a reader of my blog and not a geek, you would be very confused ;).
Well, being a fellow geek, I am prone to the same sort of problems as you when it comes to fitness. As geeks we sit in our chairs and more often than not end up looking like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Office Fitness: Replace Your Office Chair With An Exercise Ball</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/08/21/simple-office-fitness-replace-your-office-chair-with-an-exercise-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/08/21/simple-office-fitness-replace-your-office-chair-with-an-exercise-ball/</guid>
      <description>Improved posture – sitting on the ball forces you to sit up straight of you won’t be very comfortable Constant movement – Sitting for long periods of time can be bad for you, even when you exercise. Check out this recent study that was discussed on the New York Times. When you use an exercise ball for a chair, you are constantly repositioning yourself and are combatting this issue. Getting Jacked!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
