<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on Brandontreb</title>
    <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on Brandontreb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>brandontreb@gmail.com</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>brandontreb@gmail.com</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/software/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software Consultant Contracts: Fixed Bid VS Time And Materials</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/12/09/software-development-contracts-fixed-bid-vs-time-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/12/09/software-development-contracts-fixed-bid-vs-time-materials/</guid>
      <description>One of the most common questions I get from software consultants is whether or not to accept fixed bid contracts. In this post, I’m hoping to shed some light on fixed bid vs. time and materials contracts and help you make the best decision for the project at hand.
Let’s start with some definitions to help you better understand what I am talking about.
A fixed bid contract is a contract where the developer and the client agree on a price and/or timeline up front for a particular contract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development Consulting: Some Tips On Structuring Your Contracts</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/03/31/software-development-consulting-contract-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/03/31/software-development-consulting-contract-tips/</guid>
      <description>When I first started out as an independent software developer, one of things that stressed me out the most was how to structure contracts that I sent to clients. Working for a consultancy in my previous work-life I had seen contracts before, however, I never really paid enough attention to them to know what type of content went into them.
After quite a bit of research, I found an invaluable resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being An Indie Software Developer And Signing NDAs</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/02/28/indie-software-developer-signing-ndas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/02/28/indie-software-developer-signing-ndas/</guid>
      <description>Very frequently, I receive emails that go something like this:
“Hey Brandon, I have a killer project idea. Do you want to work on it? Please sign the NDA so we can talk.”
Early on when I first started consulting, I would have responded with something like “Sure send it over!” and signed the thing without hesitation. As of late, I have changed my view on NDAs; at least in this type of situation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
