<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ios on Brandontreb</title>
    <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/ios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ios on Brandontreb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>brandontreb@gmail.com</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>brandontreb@gmail.com</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/ios/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software Development Consulting: Some Tips On Structuring Your Contracts</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/03/31/software-development-consulting-contract-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/03/31/software-development-consulting-contract-tips/</guid>
      <description>When I first started out as an independent software developer, one of things that stressed me out the most was how to structure contracts that I sent to clients. Working for a consultancy in my previous work-life I had seen contracts before, however, I never really paid enough attention to them to know what type of content went into them.
After quite a bit of research, I found an invaluable resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Learned In My First Year Of iOS Consulting</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/01/01/learned-first-year-ios-consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/01/01/learned-first-year-ios-consulting/</guid>
      <description>Wow, I can’t believe it has already been a full year since I struck it out on my own. Last year, I published a post after my first month on doing contract iOS development. Needless to say, I have grown and learned quite a bit over the past year and I wanted to share some of those experiences.
Income While I won’t share exact numbers, I left my 6 figure/year job to pursue the indie/consulting life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back To My Roots</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2013/06/12/back-to-my-roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2013/06/12/back-to-my-roots/</guid>
      <description>I wrote my very first blog post back in July of 2008 when I start iCodeBlog.com. I started the blog because I saw a huge need for iOS development tutorials on the web and really wanted to help others as I progressed in my development.
Well, quite a bit has changed since then. I have written books, spoken at conferences, and built and shipped over 40 iOS applications. Since selling iCodeblog in 2009, I have really let my passion for blogging fizzle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
