<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Brandontreb</title>
    <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Brandontreb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>brandontreb@gmail.com</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>brandontreb@gmail.com</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/uncategorized/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Become An Indie Game Developer</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/06/13/how-to-become-an-indie-game-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/06/13/how-to-become-an-indie-game-developer/</guid>
      <description>[Article Link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Number One Feature Request For iOS 6</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/06/08/my-number-one-feature-request-for-ios-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/06/08/my-number-one-feature-request-for-ios-6/</guid>
      <description>Fix the Snooze button! I have no idea how this UI component got to Apple’s review team and they were like ”Yep, that looks beautiful! Ship it!”. If Apple changes the snooze button and slaps a 6 on iOS, I will be happy. If not, more rants to follow. Stay tuned….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If There Was Ever A Time To Submit A Show HN Article, It&amp;#8217;s Right Now</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/06/01/if-there-was-ever-a-time-to-submit-a-show-hn-article-its-right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/06/01/if-there-was-ever-a-time-to-submit-a-show-hn-article-its-right-now/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today a post titled ”I Try to Up Vote Every ‘Show HN’ Post and You Should Too” made it to the top of HN. It basically talked about people posting “Show HN” posts are putting themselves out there and the least we can do is give them an up vote. Well, people are listening and as of this posting, there are currently 15 Show HN posts in the top 30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lua Scripting The UI For Pocket MUD Pro</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/29/lua-scripting-the-ui-for-pocket-mud-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/29/lua-scripting-the-ui-for-pocket-mud-pro/</guid>
      <description>I have just updated my MUD client [Pocket MUD Pro] to be a universal library. It was surprisingly easy to add the iPad support as most of the application was comprised of UITableViews.
The main “MUD” view was the most challenging part as it contains a couple UIWebViews, UIButons, and a UITextField. However, I chose to do something I feel is pretty cool.
Scripting The UI With Lua If I haven’t said it enough, I love lua.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jailbreak iOS 5.1.1 With Absinthe 2.0 &#43; More Watch Dev Coming</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/25/jailbreak-ios-5-1-1-with-absinthe-2-0-more-watch-dev-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/25/jailbreak-ios-5-1-1-with-absinthe-2-0-more-watch-dev-coming/</guid>
      <description>The GreenPois0n team has just announced Absinthe 2.0 allowing users of all iDevices (except Apple TV 3) to jailbreak iOS 5.1.1. This is especially good news for me as I can now continue development on my jailbroken app for the inPulse watch, iOS notifier. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incredible List Of Popular Indie iOS/Android/Steam Titles On Sale</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/24/incredible-list-of-popular-indie-iosandroidsteam-titles-on-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/24/incredible-list-of-popular-indie-iosandroidsteam-titles-on-sale/</guid>
      <description>We believe that developers should have the freedom to price their games how they like, without interference from the online stores that sell the games. Why? Because it allows us to promote our games more freely, as we are doing here! We rely on the ability to promote our games for our livelihood and control over pricing is an important tool for this purpose.
Because We May is doing something very incredible here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Me At 360iDev 2012</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/24/join-me-at-360idev-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/24/join-me-at-360idev-2012/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned this on Twitter last week, so I might as well post it here to make it more official. My talk Making Your Games More Dynamic With Lua Scripting was accepted for 360iDev 2012! This will be my first official speaking engagement and I could not be more excited/nervous.
The Talk I have had a huge interest in lua for some time now, especially as it applies to scripting games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pocket MUD Pro Is Now Universal &#43; Promo Codes</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/23/pocket-mud-pro-is-now-universal-promo-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/23/pocket-mud-pro-is-now-universal-promo-codes/</guid>
      <description>Also, here are 10 promo codes for anyone who wants a free copy. Please comment on which code you take so others know which one’s are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The guide to implementing 2D platformers</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/23/the-guide-to-implementing-2d-platformers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/23/the-guide-to-implementing-2d-platformers/</guid>
      <description>http://higherorderfun.com/blog/2012/05/20/the-guide-to-implementing-2d-platformers/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Facebook IS People</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/23/why-facebook-is-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/23/why-facebook-is-people/</guid>
      <description>This is a very well written article detailing some of the inner workings of Facebook and why its business is YOU. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Introduction To Lua</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/22/great-introduction-to-lua/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/22/great-introduction-to-lua/</guid>
      <description>(click the post title)
I have been using lua in my iOS applications for some time now. This tutorial provides a great introduction to a scripting language that most developers are very curious about. I really suggest spending a few minutes checking it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetaWatch Announces iOS Support &amp;#8211; Still Can&amp;#8217;t Compete With Pebble</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/22/metawatch-announces-ios-support-still-cant-compete-with-pebble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/05/22/metawatch-announces-ios-support-still-cant-compete-with-pebble/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who have followed my blog for a while, you know that I am a huge geek for smart watches. I had the first version of what is now the Pebble (inPulse) and even hacked a jailbroken iOS app to interface with it.
MetaWatch has been around for quite some time now and looks *ok *, however their latest update appears to be completely in response to Allerta’s announcement/success of Pebble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pocket MUD Pro Released &#43; Promo Codes</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/03/29/pocket-mud-pro-released-promo-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/03/29/pocket-mud-pro-released-promo-codes/</guid>
      <description>I am very proud to announce a brand new version of my Pocket MUD Pro application for iPhone. I have been working very hard to make a perfect MUD client that is suitable for hardcore mud players, visually impaired mud players, and casual mud players.
Here are some of the features:
Support for all orientations Full ANSI color support Dedicated prompt Zoomable Text View Perfect rendering of MUD text (check out the maps) Very fast Hides Telnet codes from the user (unlike every other MUD client) Autoconnect on startup List of MUDS Favorite List Unlimited Command history Quickly cycle through command history Triggers using the lua scripting language Text Command Alias Lua scripted aliases Timer Support Background support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluid For Mac</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/01/19/fluid-for-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/01/19/fluid-for-mac/</guid>
      <description>As of OSX Lion, I have started to seriously loathe some of the build-it Mac apps (such as Mail, and iCal). While I previously had no issues with them, they now seem to be very clunky and crash quite often. Being a developer, I thought “why don’t I write an app that wraps web apps for you so you basically get “native web apps” that have icons and are launchable?”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon &amp;#8211; A Terrible Solution To A Huge Problem</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/01/16/amazon-a-terrible-solution-to-a-huge-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/01/16/amazon-a-terrible-solution-to-a-huge-problem/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr; Don’t buy a Kindle Fire for your kid until they resolve the parental control issues. Wifi password protection is their current solution, and it sucks.
Like many parents, I thought it would be a good idea to get a tablet device for my son so that he could play some educational games and watch some Netflix (in moderation of course). After doing quite a bit of research, I settled on the Kindle Fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Went Back To Jekyll &amp;#8211; Also Rackspace Sucks</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/01/03/why-i-went-back-to-jekyll-also-rackspace-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2012/01/03/why-i-went-back-to-jekyll-also-rackspace-sucks/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I was pretty humbled when a post of mine titled WordPress To Jekyll And Back Again made it to the front page of Hacker News. I was a little down on Jekyll for the reasons listed in that post and was feeling pretty good about my WordPress install.
At the time, I was running my own virtual instance on Rackspace cloud hosting (we’ll get to this momentarily). I also had all of the caching and optimization plugins installed and welcomed the Hacker News traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year &amp;#8211; New Theme: Focus On The Content</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/12/31/new-year-new-theme-focus-on-the-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/12/31/new-year-new-theme-focus-on-the-content/</guid>
      <description>As you may have noticed, my blog has a new (much cleaner) theme. For 2012, my blogging goals are to focus much more on content rather than flashy visuals.
I have also minimized my set up to save blogging costs (I now blog for FREE) and to simplify things greatly. Here is my new setup:
Jekyll as my “blog engine” The WPTypo WordPress Theme I ported this to Jekyll GitHub for hosting (it’s free).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SVProgressHUD Is Quickly Becoming My Favorite iOS Library</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/12/07/svprogresshud-is-quickly-becoming-my-favorite-ios-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/12/07/svprogresshud-is-quickly-becoming-my-favorite-ios-library/</guid>
      <description>From the first time I saw this effect in the Tweetie (now Twitter for iPhone), I was crazy about it. I had written my own hacks to make something close, but it was always terrible. Within the past few months, I have been using a perfect/elegant solution to this problem called SVProgressHUD.
Using this in your project is as easy as calling:
Clone SVProgressHUD On Github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tether Your iPhone Without Jailbreaking (Or Paying For It)</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/29/tether-your-iphone-without-jailbreaking-or-paying-for-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/29/tether-your-iphone-without-jailbreaking-or-paying-for-it/</guid>
      <description>With all of the buzz around the iTether App, I figured I’d offer a more permanent solution since Apple will surely yank this soon
Last year, a developer published his code for an http SOCKS proxy called iProxy. This will give your iPhone the ability to create a SOCKS server in which your laptop can connect to via the Bonjur protocol.
Once connect, all of your computer’s http traffic will be routed through the server on your iPhone essentially giving you free tethering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caterpillar 1.1 Released</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/22/caterpillar-1-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/22/caterpillar-1-1-released/</guid>
      <description>I have just released the update to my Centipede clone called Caterpillar. For those of you who don’t know, I am doing a 6 part series on how to create this game over at MobileTuts+.
This update adds some interesting functionality on which I will be blogging about in the near future.
I have added iAds to my cocos2D project and when the iAds fail to serve (which is about 75% of the time), I replace them with Admob ads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Plugin For iOS Developers And Bloggers</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/21/wordpress-plugin-for-ios-developers-and-bloggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/21/wordpress-plugin-for-ios-developers-and-bloggers/</guid>
      <description>This plugin looks to be super useful for people wanting to blog about iOS apps. It even supports the affiliate urls.
In any post or page, insert the following shortcode: [ios-app id=”1234”] (where “1234″ is your application’s App Store ID).
You can also specify a download link like this: [ios-app id=”1234” download_url=”http://www.yourlinktrackerurl.com”]
Download The Plugin Here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caterpillar-HD Now In The App Store: Tutorial Series To Follow</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/16/caterpillar-hd-now-in-the-app-store-tutorial-series-to-follow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/16/caterpillar-hd-now-in-the-app-store-tutorial-series-to-follow/</guid>
      <description>I have just released the update to my Centipede clone called Caterpillar. For those of you who don’t know, I am doing a 6 part series on how to create this game over at MobileTuts+.
This update adds some interesting functionality on which I will be blogging about in the near future.
I have added iAds to my cocos2D project and when the iAds fail to serve (which is about 75% of the time), I replace them with Admob ads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voices That Matter Conference: Highlights</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/16/voices-that-matter-conference-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/16/voices-that-matter-conference-highlights/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend, I attended the voices that matter conference as a sponsor for a new product my team is working called MaaSive. We had an absolute blast at the conference and I learned quite a bit from all of the speakers.
Here were a few of my favorite parts:
Keynote by Graeme Devine For those of you who don’t know Graeme is a legend in the game development industry. He was responsible for titles such as Quake 3, 7th guest, and Halo Wars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress To Jekyll And Back Again</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/14/wordpress-to-jekyll-and-back-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/11/14/wordpress-to-jekyll-and-back-again/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, I jumped ship on WordPress and moved to Jekyll after reading this post on Hacker News. I wanted to be 1337! I wanted to ditch the whale that was WordPress.
Well, it was quite a run, but in the end I decided to revert back to WordPress. Although Jekyll is much faster than WordPress, here were my issues:
Build Times As my post count grew, so did the time to compile my jekyll site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
