<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Brandontreb</title>
    <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Brandontreb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>brandontreb@gmail.com</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>brandontreb@gmail.com</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/articles/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trying Something New</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/04/15/trying-something-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/04/15/trying-something-new/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr: micro.blog is pretty cool.
I have recently been thinking about my process of blogging / tweeting / facebooking / etc.. and have realized that I&amp;rsquo;m burnt out on all three. I LOVE to write. I started one of the first successful iOS Blogs, published numerous (software development books)[http://manning.com/trebitowski], and have been blogging since 2008. Here are a bit of thoughts about the various platforms and ultimately my solution.
twitter Having over 4,000 followers on Twitter I used to find tremendous value in the platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Creating A Call Flow Can Help Your Software Sales Calls</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2017/04/07/how-creating-a-call-flow-helps-sales-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2017/04/07/how-creating-a-call-flow-helps-sales-calls/</guid>
      <description>In 2008, I was still in college. I had just landed my first job with a small consultancy as their first iOS developer replacing their outsourced Ukrainian team. Within my first week on the job, the CEO asked me to jump on a sales call as the technical lead. This absolutely terrified me. I remember doing things like ensuring that I had a full glass of water so my throat wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get so dry (it still did).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals For 2015</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/12/29/goals-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/12/29/goals-2015/</guid>
      <description>It cannot be overstated that writing down one’s goals is critical to acheiving them. Pair that with sharing them with others who might help keep you accountable and your probabilty of achieving those goals goes way up.
With this in mind, I have decided to share my 2015 goals here on my blog in hopes that I will do a better job of acheiving them in the new year. I tried to focus on more measurable goals rather than things like “eat better” and “exercise more”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development Consulting: Some Tips On Structuring Your Contracts</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/03/31/software-development-consulting-contract-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/03/31/software-development-consulting-contract-tips/</guid>
      <description>When I first started out as an independent software developer, one of things that stressed me out the most was how to structure contracts that I sent to clients. Working for a consultancy in my previous work-life I had seen contracts before, however, I never really paid enough attention to them to know what type of content went into them.
After quite a bit of research, I found an invaluable resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being An Indie Software Developer And Signing NDAs</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/02/28/indie-software-developer-signing-ndas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/02/28/indie-software-developer-signing-ndas/</guid>
      <description>Very frequently, I receive emails that go something like this:
“Hey Brandon, I have a killer project idea. Do you want to work on it? Please sign the NDA so we can talk.”
Early on when I first started consulting, I would have responded with something like “Sure send it over!” and signed the thing without hesitation. As of late, I have changed my view on NDAs; at least in this type of situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming A Software Consultant: My Backstory</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/01/31/becoming-software-consultant-backstory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/01/31/becoming-software-consultant-backstory/</guid>
      <description>I recently published a post about my first year of being an independent iPhone development consultant. The feedback from my readers was incredible, however there was one important thread on Hacker News that I wanted to address. The issues were:
One of my common hangups with these kind of posts is the lack of history as to what lead people to these consulting gigs. Where were you before, and how long were you there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Learned In My First Year Of iOS Consulting</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/01/01/learned-first-year-ios-consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2014/01/01/learned-first-year-ios-consulting/</guid>
      <description>Wow, I can’t believe it has already been a full year since I struck it out on my own. Last year, I published a post after my first month on doing contract iOS development. Needless to say, I have grown and learned quite a bit over the past year and I wanted to share some of those experiences.
Income While I won’t share exact numbers, I left my 6 figure/year job to pursue the indie/consulting life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back To My Roots</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2013/06/12/back-to-my-roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2013/06/12/back-to-my-roots/</guid>
      <description>I wrote my very first blog post back in July of 2008 when I start iCodeBlog.com. I started the blog because I saw a huge need for iOS development tutorials on the web and really wanted to help others as I progressed in my development.
Well, quite a bit has changed since then. I have written books, spoken at conferences, and built and shipped over 40 iOS applications. Since selling iCodeblog in 2009, I have really let my passion for blogging fizzle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;#8217;s Your Cruising Speed?</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/10/05/whats-your-cruising-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/10/05/whats-your-cruising-speed/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, I launched an application called Smart Lockscreen Creator. It was a pretty simple app that allowed you to add dynamic data (such as weather) to your wallpaper and save it back out to your camera roll. The idea is to improve the functionality of the user’s lockscreen. It did very well on launch (and even made it to #1 in the Israel App Store). At the peak, I was selling about 600 copies per day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Me At The Voices That Matter iOS Conference</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/09/07/join-me-at-the-voices-that-matter-ios-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/09/07/join-me-at-the-voices-that-matter-ios-conference/</guid>
      <description>In November, I will be attending the Voices That Matter iOS Developers conference. It will be my third time attending, and I can’t recommend it enough. One major change from this year however is, I will be attending as a sponsor. A new company/project (currently in private alpha) will be participating as a sponsor at the conference.
We intend to have a table set up with multiple computers and devices so you can check out our product first hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Great Pixel Art Tutorial And Free Resource Sites For Your Games</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/08/14/10-great-pixel-art-tutorial-and-free-resource-sites-for-your-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/08/14/10-great-pixel-art-tutorial-and-free-resource-sites-for-your-games/</guid>
      <description>I don’t usually create “list” posts, however I wanted to share a grouping of resources I have been collecting over the past few months. As you may have noticed, I’m a bit of a Pixel Art fanatic and wanted to share with you the tutorials that helped to get me started as well as some sites offering some high quality free pixel art.
Keep in mind that some of these sites have similar content, however they all take a slightly different approach in teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocos2D Tutorial &amp;#8211; Dynamically Coloring Sprites</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/07/30/cocos2d-tutorial-dynamically-coloring-sprites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/07/30/cocos2d-tutorial-dynamically-coloring-sprites/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever seen a game (such as Tiny Tower) that contains similar sprites that only vary by certain attributes (coloring, shading, accessories, etc…)? I would often wonder how long it would take the artists to create each permutation of these sprites. After discovering that you can call a method on a CCSprite called setColor, I realized how most of this customization is done in code.
This tutorial will be a continuation of my last post about creating your own Bitizen in Photoshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixel Art Character Tutorial &amp;#8211; Creating And Customizing A Bitizen</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/07/16/pixel-art-character-tutorial-creating-and-customizing-a-bitizen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/07/16/pixel-art-character-tutorial-creating-and-customizing-a-bitizen/</guid>
      <description>This will be a continuation of my last pixel art tutorial about configuring Photoshop for Pixel Art. For the past month or so, both my wife an I have been pretty addicted to this amazing game called Tiny Tower created by Nimble Bits. The biggest draw for me to this game isn’t the fact that it has great simulation style game mechanics, it’s the fact that it was created using Pixel Art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Photoshop For Pixel Art</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/07/02/configuring-photoshop-for-pixel-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/07/02/configuring-photoshop-for-pixel-art/</guid>
      <description>First things first. My wife and I had welcomed a new baby boy into the world on Monday so you guys are going to have to see the obligatory “dad” pics.
Here they are
Ok, now that’s past us, let’s chat about pixel art. I have always been a HUGE fan of pixel art both in games and as a form of art. As an aspiring game developer (games coming soon 😉 ), I found pixel art a great fit for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing iOS 4 In Action &#43; Free Chapter!</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/06/18/announcing-ios-4-in-action-free-chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/06/18/announcing-ios-4-in-action-free-chapter/</guid>
      <description>Wow, I can’t believe it has been over a year since the release of my book iPhone And iPad In Action. Since then, we have sold over 6,000 copies and have just have released in numerous languages!
As with all iOS (tech books really), my book was almost outdated the moment it hit the shelves due to Apple’s constant SDK release cycle. My book ended with “here is what’s coming in iOS 4…”, and didn’t hit the shelves until after iOS 4 was released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check Out AutoCorrector &#43; Promo Codes!</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/05/27/check-out-autocorrector-promo-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/05/27/check-out-autocorrector-promo-codes/</guid>
      <description>So, this blog post might sound like a lame press release, but I actually do want to talk about a cool app some buddies of mine created. Just read it in a cheesy used car salesman voice and it will be a lot less more enjoyable.
The Problem Have you ever tried to type shorthand text to a friend and it come out completely wrong? For example: AFK -&amp;gt; AFT, AKA -&amp;gt; Aja.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half Off iPhone And Android Books From Manning Publishing Today</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/04/14/half-off-iphone-and-android-books-from-manning-publishing-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/04/14/half-off-iphone-and-android-books-from-manning-publishing-today/</guid>
      <description>Last year I wrote the second edition of iPhone and iPad In Action. It was published by Manning Publishing and today they are offering half off all of their mobile software development books!
Simply use the code:
dotd0414 when you check out at manning.com for a half price discount on the following titles:
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt; This deal is only available for today &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;April 14th&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;, so go right now&amp;amp;#8230; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div style=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Officially Running On Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/04/06/officially-running-on-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/04/06/officially-running-on-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Well, I have finally made the switch from WordPress to Jekyll and couldn’t be happier. Here are some of the bonuses I have seen thus far.
SPEED: Just click around on my site. It is screaming fast now. Resources: Checking top on my server reveals that I have a TON of extra resources (which makes sense since Jekyll sites are way more lightweight). Ease of blogging: Ok, WordPress was pretty easy too, however, I was really starting to get sick of the post interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free App Idea: Drop Tunes</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/03/01/free-app-idea-drop-tunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/03/01/free-app-idea-drop-tunes/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps this already exists, if so, please link me to it.
The idea
Drop music into your Dropbox folder on your computer. Then open up the app which presents you with an iPod like interface for this music.
The genius
What’s great about it is, you have all of you music on your iPhone without using up disk space. Of course you may need to upgrade your Dropbox account to something greater than 2GBs to see any real value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Lockscreen Creator Released &#43; Promo Codes</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/02/24/smart-lockscreen-creator-released-promo-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/02/24/smart-lockscreen-creator-released-promo-codes/</guid>
      <description>My latest iOS app, Smart Lockscreen Creator has just released on iPhone for $.99.
Download It Here
The Idea Currently your lockscreen on your iOS device is nothing more than a pretty watch with a background. Jailbreakers have solved this issue with an incredible application called intelliscreen, which adds lots of interesting information to it. However, you and I are Apple fanboys and won’t violate our precious iPhones with jailbreaking. Enter Smart Lockscreen Creator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&amp;#8217;s Elementary My Dear Watson</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/02/15/its-elementary-my-dear-watson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/02/15/its-elementary-my-dear-watson/</guid>
      <description>Now, I’m not going to give you a rundown on it as I’m sure that you can (or have already) read it on a website far more popular than mine. I just wanted to publicly geek out for a second…
I was watching the episode of Jeopardy with my wife, and at first glance she was like “duh, of course a computer could win at Jeopardy”. This made me realize that to a non engineer, this seems like a trivial task since computers are magical Facebook boxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Of The Mondays</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/02/14/case-of-the-mondays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/02/14/case-of-the-mondays/</guid>
      <description>The other day, I was faced with an interesting programming challenge and wanted to share my solution. I just submitted a pretty interesting app to the app store that does a number of things (more details soon). Among those things is the ability to generate a calendar.
The Problem Generating the calendar was the easy part, however when displayed, I wanted it to highlight every Monday of the month. This turned out to be a bit trickier than I imagined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell (For Now) iDevBlogADay</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/01/20/farewell-for-now-idevblogaday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/01/20/farewell-for-now-idevblogaday/</guid>
      <description>Hey guys,
I wanted to thank everyone for letting me be a part of the iDevBlogADay community. You guys have been super supportive and I really appreciate all of the commenting, retweeting, and upvoting of my iDevBlogADay articles.
I have found myself in a position with life (work + family) where I may no longer be able to consistently write a post per week. So, after 2 months of writing, it is time for me to pass the torch to the next blogger on the list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Pi]mp Wallpaper</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/01/03/pimp-wallpaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/01/03/pimp-wallpaper/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does Your Workspace Look Like?</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/30/what-does-your-workspace-look-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/30/what-does-your-workspace-look-like/</guid>
      <description>I am always very fascinated with the workspaces of others and frequently check out Lifehacker’s posts on their featured workspaces. So, for this iDevBlogADay post, I thought I would keep it short and simple with a request. I want to see (and I’m sure others do too) photos of YOUR workspaces (especially those of you with standing desks).
Seeing someone’s work area is especially inspring to me, I love seeing where others create and what they surround themselves with for inspiration and motivation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Storage Wallpaper</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/24/cloud-storage-wallpaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/24/cloud-storage-wallpaper/</guid>
      <description>This is my current desktop image. I thought is was pretty sweet so I’ll share it with you all.
Merry Christmas!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does He Have A Memory Leak?</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/22/does-he-have-a-memory-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/22/does-he-have-a-memory-leak/</guid>
      <description>My wife has this interesting problem of having vivid dreams about whatever she was last watching/discussing before bed. Last night, I was explaining to her all about memory leaks as I had a discussion with a coworker earlier in the day about them. She was curious, so I gave her a very simple explanation in which she could understand.
Later in the night (about 3 am), my son woke up screaming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advertising Now Available</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/20/advertising-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/20/advertising-now-available/</guid>
      <description>I am now offering advertising in the sidebar for the killer price of $10. I felt that the Google Adsense ads looked super spammy and this is a much cleaner way to handle things.
So please give me a hand with these server costs, show off your sweet apps/site, and purchase an ad on the blog.
Either click the Advertise Here button on the side or click this link http://bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That&amp;#8217;s It! I Quit Programming.</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/17/thats-it-i-quit-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/17/thats-it-i-quit-programming/</guid>
      <description>Because I could never make something this cool/impressive:
YouTube – Introducing Word Lens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link: Minecraft Like Rendering Experiments in OpenGL 4 &amp;#8211; Codeflow</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/13/link-minecraft-like-rendering-experiments-in-opengl-4-codeflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/12/13/link-minecraft-like-rendering-experiments-in-opengl-4-codeflow/</guid>
      <description>I found this article while browsing reddit and was blown away. I have been a little mystified at the potential algorithms used by notch to render the terrain in Minecraft.
This provides a killer explanation of some interesting algorithms that can be used to generate such worlds. It also contains the source code that you can download and play with.
Minecraft Like Rendering Experiments in OpenGL 4 – Codeflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XCode Tips And Shortcuts To Improve Your Workflow</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/11/18/xcode-tips-and-shortcuts-to-improve-your-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/11/18/xcode-tips-and-shortcuts-to-improve-your-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is my first #iDevBlogADay post and I wanted to give a quick intro before jumping in. My name is Brandon Trebitowski and I’m a software developer and author from Albuquerque, New Mexico. I graduated from the University of New Mexico in 2008 with a bachelors degree in computer science. For the past 2 years, I have been writing mobile applications (primarily for the iPhone) for ELC Technologies.
I also started http://icodeblog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RE: Android Developer Income Report</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/11/08/re-android-developer-income-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/11/08/re-android-developer-income-report/</guid>
      <description>This article was a very interesting with some insight into the Android Market. Basically, this indie Android developer has published 6 free applications and is making more than $1,000.00 per month off of advertisements.
None of my apps has been ever promoted in Top of Android Market
I am providing only free apps (mostly due of Android Market limitations)
Even if I would be able to sell apps I would not use it as main income source… (I believe that you still can make more from ads…)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What not to do in life | TKs weblog</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/11/05/what-not-to-do-in-life-tks-weblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/11/05/what-not-to-do-in-life-tks-weblog/</guid>
      <description>Here is a great article about some advice given to a 22 year old starting his life journey. These points are applicable to anyone, but found them especially applicable to software developers in general.
http://www.tawheedkader.com/2010/11/what-not-to-do-in-life/
Here are a few that I particularly enjoyed
Do not ever work
Picasso used to paint all the time, Henry Moore sculpt the whole day. Others would have thought they were working themselves to death. They actually were reenergizing and reinvigorating themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Pretty Much Sums It Up</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/22/this-pretty-much-sums-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/22/this-pretty-much-sums-it-up/</guid>
      <description>Source</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Traits Of A Successful Developer</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/16/6-traits-of-a-successful-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/16/6-traits-of-a-successful-developer/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoyed this article on traits of developers.
http://www.turnleafdesign.com/6-traits-of-successful-developers
In my experience, developers tend to become arrogant and totally ignore #1 (see Windows Devs). I feel that this is the most important trait of all.
“For a developer to be successful over any period of time a continued commitment to learning is absolutely vital. The field is too large, too quickly changing, and too in depth for any developer to ever “know it all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEO: Works Every Time</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/16/seo-works-every-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/16/seo-works-every-time/</guid>
      <description>So I received an internal email at work the other day about how we could SEO our company website (http://elctech.com). Here was my suggestion:
“Just put up a few tags that state (in this order) Rails, Coding, Consulting, Porn, Free Porn, Porn on Rails, Viagra, iPhone, development, hot chicks, elc.
Guaranteed hits!”
Genius right? So after a while, a fellow employee (@maxmurphy) suggested we implement this rails solution:
Perfect!
Feel free to steal this and you too can be an SEO Guru!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great HTML5 Infographic</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/07/great-html5-infographic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/07/great-html5-infographic/</guid>
      <description>This info graphic just about sums it up in terms of what is HTML, and why we should care. It includes browser readyness, various API support, comparison of competition, and more. Check it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HECK YES C Macro, For When Something Is REALLY True</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/04/15/heck-yes-c-macro-for-when-something-is-really-true/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/04/15/heck-yes-c-macro-for-when-something-is-really-true/</guid>
      <description>Quite possibly the most useful macro you will ever use.
Now if only I could replace semi colons with exclamation points…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs For OSX Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/01/29/emacs-for-osx-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/01/29/emacs-for-osx-is-out/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The iPad Is Out And It Sounds Like iPod While Plugging Your Nose</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/01/27/the-ipad-is-out-and-it-sounds-like-ipod-while-plugging-your-nose/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/01/27/the-ipad-is-out-and-it-sounds-like-ipod-while-plugging-your-nose/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch Out Apple, The Kindle Dev Kit Is Almost Live</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/01/21/watch-out-apple-the-kindle-dev-kit-is-almost-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/01/21/watch-out-apple-the-kindle-dev-kit-is-almost-live/</guid>
      <description>With the success of the Apple App Store, it seems that everyone is wanting a piece of the pie.
Amazon is now looking to throw their hat into the ring and is releasing their own dev kit for their ever so popular Kindle.
http://www.amazon.com/gp/feature.html/?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;docId=1000476231
It appears that big name game developers Electronic Arts is also getting involved (WTH?!?!)
This just seems like it will be an epic fail. Who really wants to play video games on their Kindle?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Monkey Music Video</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/01/20/code-monkey-music-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/01/20/code-monkey-music-video/</guid>
      <description>Watching this video makes me appreciate the fact that I work from home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Redbox &amp;#8211; How To Get Free DVDs</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/01/04/hacking-redbox-how-to-get-free-dvds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/01/04/hacking-redbox-how-to-get-free-dvds/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;wp-caption-text&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Image via Wikipedia &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; I was at Wally-World the other day getting a movie from RedBox with my wife when I noticed some guy enter in a code into the machine. The code was BREAKROOM. After watching him for a moment, I realized this code entitled him a free DVD rental.
Now, RedBox is pretty stinking cheap ($1.50/night), but if you’re an avid movie watcher, this really adds up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great List Of Algorithm Programming Tutorials</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/12/17/great-list-of-algorithm-programming-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/12/17/great-list-of-algorithm-programming-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>Recently TopCoder.com posted a list of algorithm tutorials from some of their “top coders”.
The tutorials are very comprehensive and pretty much sum my undergraduate computer science degree up in one page This page is a great resource for anyone that does any amount of coding…
Some of the tutorials include:
Greedy algorithms Various sort and search techniques Data structures Graph theory Here is the link to the Top Coder Tutorials:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Tip Of The Day #2 &amp;#8211; Difference Between i&#43;&#43; and &#43;&#43;i</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/12/04/programming-tip-of-the-day-2-difference-between-i-and-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/12/04/programming-tip-of-the-day-2-difference-between-i-and-i/</guid>
      <description>To some, this should seem a bit obvious and if I am insulting your intelligence by discussing it, I am sorry. But, one of the main reasons I want to discuss this topic is, I was asked this question in a job interview for Lockheed Martin.
What is the difference between i++ and ++i?
The answer is actually quite simple.
i++ first evaluates the value of i and then increments it ++i increments the value of i and then evaluates it Here is a brief example to demonstrate what I mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Tip Of The Day #1 &amp;#8211; Ternary Operator</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/12/03/programming-tip-of-the-day-1-ternary-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/12/03/programming-tip-of-the-day-1-ternary-operator/</guid>
      <description>So, I though I’d start this series called Programming Tip Of The Day to write about useful things I come across in programming. Both to educate my readers and as a personal archive of ideas and tips.
I will kick it off today with a quick rant about the ternary operator. I &amp;lt;3 the ternary operator. It’s quick, efficient and saves a lot of ugly code.
For those of you who don’t know, the ternary operator is made up of 3 elements: The condition and two results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac OSX Tip: Hotkey To Hide/Show the Dock</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/12/02/mac-osx-tip-hotkey-to-hideshow-the-dock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/12/02/mac-osx-tip-hotkey-to-hideshow-the-dock/</guid>
      <description>While mashing the keyboard (as I often do when debuggin poorly written outsourced code), I stumbled upon a very useful OSX hotkey.
⌘-option-d This command will cause the Dock to go in and out of auto-hide mode.
Not the most useful, but very helpful to geeks like me who rearrange their desktop every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First learn computer science and all the theory. Next develop a programming style. Then forget all that and just hack.</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/25/first-learn-computer-science-and-all-the-theory-next-develop-a-programming-style-then-forget-all-that-and-just-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/25/first-learn-computer-science-and-all-the-theory-next-develop-a-programming-style-then-forget-all-that-and-just-hack/</guid>
      <description>George Carrette [1990].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Class To Interface With Many URL Shortening Services</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/16/php-class-to-interface-with-many-url-shortening-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/16/php-class-to-interface-with-many-url-shortening-services/</guid>
      <description>With the explosion of Twitter and such services, the need to have long URLs shortened has drastically increased. Naturally, many services to shorten URLs have sprung up as well.
Most of these services (that are worth using), have some sort of API that will allow developers to send a long URL to them, have it shortened and then returned. This type of service allows other developers to write applications that have the ability to shorten URLs right inside of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$13 Dollar Discount On Programming Books From Manning Publishing</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/13/13-dollar-discount-on-programming-books-from-manning-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/13/13-dollar-discount-on-programming-books-from-manning-publishing/</guid>
      <description>The publishing that I’m writing the book for is having a huge Friday the 13th sale. They are offering a $13 discount on all of their books. For those of you who don’t know, Manning publishes all of the “In Action” books.
All you have to do is go to the site and enter the coupon code:
fri13 when checking out and you will get the discount. Although my book iPhone In Action 2nd Edition hasn’t been released yet, Manning has some other killer programming books for sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/13/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/13/programming/</guid>
      <description>Image taken from abtrusegoose</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money You Might Be Missing Out On &amp;#8211; LinkShare API Integration</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/12/money-you-might-be-missing-out-on-linkshare-api-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/12/money-you-might-be-missing-out-on-linkshare-api-integration/</guid>
      <description>As you may know, I am the developer of the site FreshApps.com. One thing we had been doing to make some extra money is to use Linkshare to be an affiliate for Apple.
If you don’t know, Linkshare is a service that allows you to become an affiliate of thousands of companies. You simply select one of the companies products, get the linkshare link, and put the link on your site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object-oriented programming is an exceptionally bad idea which could only have originated in California.</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/11/object-oriented-programming-is-an-exceptionally-bad-idea-which-could-only-have-originated-in-california/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/11/object-oriented-programming-is-an-exceptionally-bad-idea-which-could-only-have-originated-in-california/</guid>
      <description>Edsger Dijkstra</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Alice in Wonderland Poster Is Sweet</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/10/new-alice-in-wonderland-poster-is-sweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/10/new-alice-in-wonderland-poster-is-sweet/</guid>
      <description>Very stoked for this movie. Photo source ign</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was Jesus A Real Person? Great Article On Digg Today</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/10/was-jesus-a-real-person-great-article-on-digg-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/10/was-jesus-a-real-person-great-article-on-digg-today/</guid>
      <description>The culture of Digg is generally very liberal (to say the least). That is why I was very surprised to find one of the top stories of the day entitled ”Was Jesus A Real Person?”. Obviously, the comments section of the article was full of people arguing about the matter.
I found the article to be quite well written and made a stellar case for the existence of Jesus. So whether you are a believer or not, you should check it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Displaying Your FeedBurner Subscriber Count Anywhere &amp;#8211; PHP Coding Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/08/10/displaying-your-feedburner-subscriber-count-anywhere-php-coding-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/08/10/displaying-your-feedburner-subscriber-count-anywhere-php-coding-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>If you are a serious blogger (and I’m sure you are), you probably track your RSS subscribers with FeedBurner. If you don’t, you should be. One thing that has always bugged me about FeedBurner is if you ever wanted to display the number of subscribers on your blog, you were stuck using their image. The image looks like this:
I’m sure you have seen this logo everywhere. Well, not too many people know it, but FeedBurner actually has a very simple API that allows you to just get the subscriber count so you can display it however you would like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily Create And Manage SQLite Databases With A Firefox Plugin</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/08/06/easily-create-and-manage-sqlite-databases-with-a-firefox-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/08/06/easily-create-and-manage-sqlite-databases-with-a-firefox-plugin/</guid>
      <description>If you are doing any Mac, iPhone, HTML5, etc… developement, you have probably had the need for an sqlite database. So, you fire up your Terminal and start manully typing commands to do CREATEs and INSERTs.
You soon realize that this sucks and wish you had something like (shudders) PHPMyAdmin to manage your database. Well, now you do and it’s actually a lot less hiddeous than PHPMyAdmin.
Using the SQLite Manager plugin for Firefox, you can quickly CREATE, MODIFY, and DELETE sqlite databases visually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing And Deploying Rails On A Red Hat Server With Passenger</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/07/23/installing-and-deploying-rails-on-a-red-hat-server-with-passenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/07/23/installing-and-deploying-rails-on-a-red-hat-server-with-passenger/</guid>
      <description>I have long been a fan of Ruby on Rails and even jumper on board very early on. The one thing that has held me back from using it in the majority of my projects is the fact that it’s such a pain to configure with Apache.
I know what you are saying… Just switch to a more Rails friendly server. I like and know Apache. Not to mention I also host PHP apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Alice In Wonderland Movie Looks Sick</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/07/22/new-alice-in-wonderland-movie-looks-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/07/22/new-alice-in-wonderland-movie-looks-sick/</guid>
      <description>I was a big fan of the game Alice that came out for PC. It def portrayed AIW as a darker sort of movie. It looks like Tim Burton will add a similar twist to the latest Alice In Wonderland Movie. Check out the trailer above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TagACloud.com (Re)Launched!</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/07/22/tagacloud-com-relaunched/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/07/22/tagacloud-com-relaunched/</guid>
      <description>The Idea: TagACloud is a very unique idea for a website, thus it will take a little explaining to understand all the facets. To take full advantage of the site, you must be the owner or have control over your own website. The idea is to create a tag that represents your website. A tag is a descriptive phrase or a creative tagline describing your site. Once you have added your tag, it gets added to the Tag Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhoneLB.com gets a much needed update</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/06/08/iphonelb-com-gets-a-much-needed-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/06/08/iphonelb-com-gets-a-much-needed-update/</guid>
      <description>So, I started this site called iphonelb.com a few months back and left out a very important feature. The ability to edit your applications!?! What this means is, users have been testing their apps and putting in “test data” and when it comes time for release, the can’t modify it.
Another feature missing, was the ability to clean out all of your test scores.
Well, thanks to about 8 minutes of my time, this has been resolved and the feature has been added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parks &amp;#038; Recreation is to The Office as American Dad is to Family Guy</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/04/10/parks-recreation-is-to-the-office-as-american-dad-is-to-family-guy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/04/10/parks-recreation-is-to-the-office-as-american-dad-is-to-family-guy/</guid>
      <description>After seeing the show Parks and Recreation last night, I have come to the conclusion that the show is doomed to fail. Not only is it not funny, it’s jokes try to mimic the dry awkward humor of The Office. Parks and Recreation Fail!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Your Blog Traffic Using Twitter Trends</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/04/06/increasing-your-blog-traffic-using-twitter-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/04/06/increasing-your-blog-traffic-using-twitter-trends/</guid>
      <description>Twitter Trends are a very interesting part of Twitter. They are basically the most typed keywords or hashtags on twitter for a given day. Some examples might be #musicmonday or macHeist. These are fun and all but how can you use them to get traffic to my website/blog…
Find Trends That Refer To Articles People Are Linking To? Well, often times trends refer to words associated with website articles, videos, images, etc… For example, the other day, the word mashable was trending on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I freakin hate this page&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/04/04/i-freakin-hate-this-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/04/04/i-freakin-hate-this-page/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexa Gets a Much Needed Update</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/04/03/alexa-gets-a-much-needed-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/04/03/alexa-gets-a-much-needed-update/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twouble With Twitter Video</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/27/twouble-with-twitter-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/27/twouble-with-twitter-video/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so I am sure you have seen this video by now, but I just had to post it because it’s flippin hilarious.
This perfectly describes mine (and others) Twitter obsession. Kinda sad actually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google In Real Life Using Google Classic</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/26/google-in-real-life-using-google-classic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/26/google-in-real-life-using-google-classic/</guid>
      <description>I depend on Google way too much for spell checking, simple math, and looking up things I don’t know off the top of my head.
It’s sad because often my first instinct when handwriting something or even looking for a lost object in my house is to “Google it”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Dugg Story of Today &amp;#8211; I hate Dane Cook</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/24/top-dugg-story-of-today-i-hate-dane-cook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/24/top-dugg-story-of-today-i-hate-dane-cook/</guid>
      <description>LOL, SlightyOverDressed.com had a post that made it to the top of DIGG today simply titled “I Hate Dane Cook”. That’s freakin hilarious.
Here’s the link. http://slightlyoverdressed.com/i-hate-dane-cook/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Web Application That Will Be Useful For iPhone Games Developers</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/12/new-web-application-that-will-be-useful-for-iphone-games-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/12/new-web-application-that-will-be-useful-for-iphone-games-developers/</guid>
      <description>So, after downloading many iPhone games and talking with a ton of iphone developers, I have a found a huge need in the community. Over the next week I will be developing a killer web application with a web service API that will be free to iPhone developers to use.
I am not going to give out any details at the moment, but be sure to subscribe to my RSS feed as I will be blogging about it through out next week (Spring Break = Time to develop).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Only Twitter API PHP Class You Will Ever Need</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/27/the-only-twitter-api-php-class-you-will-ever-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/27/the-only-twitter-api-php-class-you-will-ever-need/</guid>
      <description>Note Twitter has switchted their entire interface to use OAUTH and this class no longer works (I should probably change the title hahaha). I will post an oauth connection tutorial in the near future, so make sure to subscribe to my RSS feed for all of the sweet sweets updates!
Cheers!
So, I started writing a Twitter API Programming series last week… Here is part 1. I have found that there is not much else to teach when it comes to interfacing with Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter API Programming Tutorial With PHP &amp;#8211; Intro</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/20/twitter-api-programming-tutorial-with-php-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/20/twitter-api-programming-tutorial-with-php-intro/</guid>
      <description>I have recently started using Twitter and completely fell in love with it. Being a programming, this naturally made me want to develop applications for interfacing with it. So, I scoured the internet (checking Twitter’s website as well) to find good *simple tutorials for doing this. After searching for a while, I couldn’t really find any. Ok, I lied, I found a few but they were terrible. I hate tutorials that assume the reader knows more than they actually do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Practices &amp;#8211; Frequency and Size of Posts</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/18/blogging-practices-frequency-and-size-of-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/18/blogging-practices-frequency-and-size-of-posts/</guid>
      <description>If you have ever had your own blog, you may have at one point been faced with a question. How often should I write a blog post and how long should each post be?
I have been thinking about this since I started blogging. It is a common thought that you must write a post every single day in order to increase/maintain traffic. But, is this really true? For busy people with families and lives (that aren’t blogging) might have a tough time writing a new content-rich post every single day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buzzword</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/17/buzzword/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/17/buzzword/</guid>
      <description>The ultimate party game has arrived in the App Store! If you are a fan of the game Catch-Phrase, then you will love Buzzword. In this fast-paced game, do whatever it takes to get your team to guess the word or phrase. Give them clues – talk, use your hands, jump around. Once they guess, pass it quick. You don’t want to be caught with the game at the buzz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Connect Facebook To Twitter</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/17/how-to-connect-facebook-to-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/17/how-to-connect-facebook-to-twitter/</guid>
      <description>With the growing popularity of both Twitter and Facebook, one could obviously see a need to link them together. Whether you primarily use Twitter or Facebook, this tutorial will show you step by step, how to update your Facebook status by posting to your Twitter account.
So, how can you update your Facebook status with a text message? Well, Twitter offers this great functionality that allows you to post a “Tweet” via text message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Focus Of This Blog</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/17/the-focus-of-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/02/17/the-focus-of-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this blog will be primarily to share my programming knowledge through coding tutorials.
I will be writing tutorials based on the programming language that I am currently excited about. These will be anywhere from objective-c to ruby on rails to .NET. Whatever strikes my fancy.
Along the road, I will also be sharing my art (photo and drawing) as well as anything else I find interesting.
So just sit back and enjoy the magic of code!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
