<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wordpress on Brandontreb</title>
    <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/wordpress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wordpress on Brandontreb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>brandontreb@gmail.com</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>brandontreb@gmail.com</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/wordpress/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Considering Leaving WordPress For Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/03/28/considering-leaving-wordpress-for-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/03/28/considering-leaving-wordpress-for-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>So, after my 6 year relationship with WordPress, I have been having some strong feelings for another (blog engine). Jekyll does everything that I want my wordpress to do.
Not suck at security Not be bloated Not have a sucky post editor Expense – I have a few blogs hosted on Rackspace and my bill has gotten pretty pricey. I’m hoping to host my Jekyll site on App Engine for frizzle (free).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweet Press 3.2 Update &amp;#8211; Sidebar Widget</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/02/16/tweet-press-3-2-update-sidebar-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2011/02/16/tweet-press-3-2-update-sidebar-widget/</guid>
      <description>I have recently had an overwhelming number of requests for a sidebar widget that displays your recent Tweetpress photos. Well, it’s finally here! The update was actually quite trivial to make. If I had known how simple it would be, I would have made it months ago.
Make sure you update to the latest version: tweetpress 3.2
How to use it
In the WordPress admin, click on Appearance and the Widgets from the sidebar menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweetpress Plugin Updated</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/10/28/tweetpress-plugin-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/10/28/tweetpress-plugin-updated/</guid>
      <description>I have just posted an update to my plugin Tweetpress! In case you don’t know, Tweetpress is a plugin I created that allows you to post images to your WordPress blog from mobile Twitter clients instead of a 3rd party service like Twitpic. Here is what’s new in this version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great WordPress Plugin To Connect Your WordPress Blog To Your Tumblr</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/17/great-wordpress-plugin-to-connect-your-wordpress-blog-to-your-tumblr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/09/17/great-wordpress-plugin-to-connect-your-wordpress-blog-to-your-tumblr/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so maybe this is stupid, reposting your own content in multiple areas. As far as SEO goes, it may not be the best idea. However, I really love Tumblr and I really love WordPress. I can’t seem to part with either yet I don’t quite have the time for both.
I put out a quick tweet earlier today (and this is why I flippin love Twitter), asking if anyone knew of a good way to connect WordPress to Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress For iPhone/iPad NSXMLParserErrorDomain Error 64 Resolved</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/08/30/wordpress-for-iphoneipad-nsxmlparsererrordomain-error-64-resolved/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/08/30/wordpress-for-iphoneipad-nsxmlparsererrordomain-error-64-resolved/</guid>
      <description>If you have a WordPress blog and an iPhone/iPad, then you most likely have the WordPress for iOS app. If you don’t, you should.
Over the past couple of days, I have been receiving the following error when trying to add my blog to the iPhone app.
After scouring the internet, I found that this could be the result of a few issues.
Special characters in a post body that are not supported by NSXMLParser Special characters in a comment Invalid post or comment RSS An error in a theme/plugin file For me, this turned out to be an issue with the comments RSS feed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedburner Anywhere Plugin Updated</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/08/27/feedburner-anywhere-plugin-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/08/27/feedburner-anywhere-plugin-updated/</guid>
      <description>I have updated my WordPress plugin Feedburner Anywhere. In case you are unfamiliar with it, it’s a plugin that allows you to output your Feedburner subscriber count anywhere on your blog.
**The Problem: **Since Google took over Feedburner, I feel that it has been quite unreliable. A few times a week, Feedburner would return 0 for your subscriber count. This was an issue with the plugin. If the return value was 0 when the plugin pulled and cached the feedburner data, you would look like you had no subscribers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Version of TweetPress 3.0</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/07/06/test-version-of-tweetpress-3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/07/06/test-version-of-tweetpress-3-0/</guid>
      <description>So WordPress 3.0 has broken Tweetpress for many people. If you are daring, willing to help, and experiencing issues with Tweetpress, please download the 3.0 test build of Tweetpress and install it on your WordPress blog.
Here are your next steps after installation:
Make sure you add your Twitter username and Password to the Tweetpress settings in your wp-admin and save it Attempt to post a photo to Twitter using Twitter for iPhone If it works, you win, let me know, if not do this: go back to the tweetpress admin in wp-admin click the log link at the very bottom copy the text and email it to brandontreb [at] gmail [dot] com with the subject “Tweetpress Log” This will really help me troubleshoot the issues that everyone has been having.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedburner Anywhere Plugin Released</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/06/08/feedburner-anywhere-plugin-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/06/08/feedburner-anywhere-plugin-released/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;wp-caption-text&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Image via CrunchBase &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; I have just released another WordPress plugin called Feedburner Anywhere.
What it does is allow you to display your RSS subscriber count anywhere on your blog.
You have the choice of using the built-in widget, embedding it in your posts/pages, or a combination of both.
Check out my sidebar for an example of usage.
Download Feedburner Anywhere at WordPress.org</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Load WordPress Post Images Like Mashable.com</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/04/06/dynamically-load-wordpress-post-images-like-mashable-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/04/06/dynamically-load-wordpress-post-images-like-mashable-com/</guid>
      <description>What? Have you ever noticed that the content on Mashable.com loads Incredibly fast? Also, have you noticed that as you scroll the images seem to ‘fade’ in? Well, this isn’t due to some crazy h4x0r code written specifically by Mashable Engineers. It’s a simple JQuery plugin that loads the images ‘Lazily’.
The Jquery plugin can be found here and a nice tutorial for implementing it can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Coding: Programmatically Add Post Tags (and other meta info)</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/03/17/wordpress-coding-programmatically-add-post-tags-and-other-meta-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/03/17/wordpress-coding-programmatically-add-post-tags-and-other-meta-info/</guid>
      <description>The script to do this is actually quite simple and can be used to update any post attribute.
Here is the code:
This will assign the keywords “foo”, “bar”, and “baz” to the post with ID 5. This task seems trivial, however it’s very powerful when you think about automation. For example, you could write a script to scrape a google search for your target keyword and find related keywords for each of your posts automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Programming Tip: Enable Database Error Reporting For Custom Queries</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/03/12/wordpress-programming-tip-enable-database-error-reporting-for-custom-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2010/03/12/wordpress-programming-tip-enable-database-error-reporting-for-custom-queries/</guid>
      <description>So this one should seem pretty obvious, but it wasn’t apparent to me at first. It was only after digging through the wp-db.php file that I discovered how to enable error reporting.
The Problem As you may have discovered, the wp_query() function isn’t a “one size fit’s all” solution. Often times, you may need to query the WordPress database using a custom MySQL query. Especially if you are using WordPress for anything other than a blog (ie freshapps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increase Your Twitter Following Using Your WordPress Blog</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/27/increase-your-twitter-following-using-your-wordpress-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/11/27/increase-your-twitter-following-using-your-wordpress-blog/</guid>
      <description>Download TwitPop Now
TwitPop is a WordPress plugin I wrote with one goal…To make you more popular on Twitter. There are sites that spring up from time to time claiming to get you more followers on Twitter if you follow X amount of people on the follow train. Well, now you can create your own Twitter train on your wordpress blog and really get more followers.
Instructions
Log in to your Twitter account below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TweetPress Now Supported By Twittelator Pro</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/10/06/tweetpress-now-supported-by-twittelator-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/10/06/tweetpress-now-supported-by-twittelator-pro/</guid>
      <description>For many of you this is old new. But since it’s latest release, Twittelator Pro has supported TweetPress as one of the options for Photo Posting. Here are the steps to configure Twittelator Pro:
First, make sure you have TweetPress installed on your WordPress blog by following the installation instructions here Tap the Settings tab Select WordPress from the dropdown under Choose Photo Service
** **Tap **Other Services **(you should see the WordPress logo) and then tap **Tweetpress for iPhone **</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Photos To Twitter From Your WordPress Blog With TweetPress</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/09/18/post-photos-to-twitter-from-your-wordpress-blog-with-tweetpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/09/18/post-photos-to-twitter-from-your-wordpress-blog-with-tweetpress/</guid>
      <description>Navigate to the TweetPress admin Settings &amp;gt; TweetPress Enter your Twitter username and password Press the Save Twitter Settings button TweetPress will verify your username and password with Twitter If they are incorrect, it will let you know and you must re enter them Navigate to your gallery page You should now see a form that has a text box and an upload button Click browse to find an image on your computer to post Enter your Tweet in the box Click Post It’s very quick and easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TweetPress coming soon to a Twitter Client Near You</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/09/10/tweetpress-coming-soon-to-a-twitter-client-near-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/09/10/tweetpress-coming-soon-to-a-twitter-client-near-you/</guid>
      <description>TweetPress is the WordPress plugin that gives you total control and ownership of the photos you post to Twitter, sending your traffic back to your own blog, instead of a third party site
I just finished development of this WordPress plugin and Andrew Stone of Twittelator has integrated it into his latest version of Twittelator Pro. As of this post, that version is still in review, so you will have to wait until it is approved to make use of TweetPress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Plugin To Increase Twitter Popularity</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/31/wordpress-plugin-to-increase-twitter-popularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/31/wordpress-plugin-to-increase-twitter-popularity/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress For iPhone Gets A Much Needed Update</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/25/wordpress-for-iphone-gets-a-much-needed-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2009/03/25/wordpress-for-iphone-gets-a-much-needed-update/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, the popular blogging tool WordPress released a much needed update to their iPhone application. The main features included in the update were:
Landscape mode for writing posts – This is a huge one. It was a total pain in the butt writing blog posts with the vertical keyboard Page Editing/Creation – Meh… How often do you do this? Comment Moderation – Very excited about this feature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
