<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Brandontreb</title>
    <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Brandontreb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>brandontreb@gmail.com</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>brandontreb@gmail.com</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 14:55:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brandontreb.github.io/tags/programming/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programming Languages Are Only Tools</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2019/12/22/programming-languages-are-only-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 14:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2019/12/22/programming-languages-are-only-tools/</guid>
      <description>Some young punks overheard me talking about JavaScript at lunch today. They felt it necessary to come to my table and tell me “typescript is waybetter”. They don’t realize that this sort of thing screams “I’m a junior developer! I know very little about the tech industry!”
If you are a newer developer, learn early that you are greatly limiting your potential by marrying a subset of programming languages. You will greatly increase your value by being open to learning and building in any language that is best suited for the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Blinders - Failing To See Things From A User Perspective</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/30/dev-blinders-failing-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 21:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/30/dev-blinders-failing-to/</guid>
      <description>The other day, I was having a conversation over Slack with my development team. They were working on a client project (and doing a killer job), and there was a particular UX pattern that seemed very unintuitive to me. This app was designed by the client, so there was little the dev team could do beyond making suggestions, so they went ahead and implemented it per the spec.
After fiddling around with it for a few minutes, I literally couldn&#39;t understand how to complete the particular task and had to ask the team lead for some help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips For Starting Your CS Career</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/28/tips-for-starting-your-cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 03:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/28/tips-for-starting-your-cs/</guid>
      <description>My little brother was recently in town for the holidays. He’s about to graduate from college with a CS degree, so naturally we talked about searching for a job.
I figured I would share the advice I gave to him here in hopes that it might help others.
Don’t be discouraged when you get turned down. Having hired many employees over the years, I have learned that there are so many reasons to not hire a candidate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No One Cares About Your Clever Code</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/27/no-one-cares-about-your/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/27/no-one-cares-about-your/</guid>
      <description>As developers, we spend so much time perfecting our craft. We are always on the hunt for hacks, tips, and tweaks.
We always set out to write the most clever and reusable code possible. This is all great&amp;hellip;until it’s time to ship.
I have seen it time after time. Developers over-optimizing their code, writing protocol after protocol. All the while, they slip further and further behind schedule.
When the client asks the dev about the delay on feature X, the dev proceeds to explain the super cool reusable, component-driven,state managed, highly available, future proof, buzzword, buzzword system they are creating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototypes Usually End Up In Production</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/22/prototypes-usually-end-up-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/22/prototypes-usually-end-up-in/</guid>
      <description>“Just hack a quick proof of concept, we’ll rebuild it when we get more funding.” These are some words I often hear from clients who have minimal budgets.
They generally want my team to build something small/quick/cheap to get their concept across in hopes of securing more funds down the road.
What I have learned by saying “yes” to these types of requests in the past is, those quickly hacked prototypes often end up in production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Client Deliveries Are Hard</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/14/client-deliveries-are-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 23:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/14/client-deliveries-are-hard/</guid>
      <description>I have been building software for clients for over a decade now and have come to one solid conclusion: deliveries suck.
Maybe I&#39;m just the worst developer in the world and have worked with the worst teams and have had the worst clients… but I doubt it.
I have delivered early, on time, late, with more functionality, exactly the same, and in some cases less functionality (usually due to lack of funding) and still…rough deliveries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It`s A Good Time To Be A (Good) Mobile Developer</title>
      <link>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/06/it-s-a-good-time-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 16:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com</author>
      <guid>https://brandontreb.github.io/2018/11/06/it-s-a-good-time-to/</guid>
      <description>If you are a mobile developer in 2018, and are not consulting (at least on the side), you are missing out on a huge stream of revenue.
In the early days of mobile app development (2008/2009), it was fairly easy for an iOS or Android developer to get a gig with large companies (Food Network, ESPN, huge list of other names…). At that time, mobile was so new, that none of these companies had internal resources to support this budding vertical.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
